RICHNALD CHARLES MOLEL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

M: +255753683801 E:richnaldcharles1995@gmail.com A:2115 Dar es Salaam,

Tanzania

PROFILE. ABOUT ME

I'm a Software developer with extensive experience in designing products, web apps and mobile applications. Also, as a Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry.

Experienced at driving a user experience from start-to-finish that delivers results, connects emotionally, creating and revising information architecture documents and diagrams including content diagrams, wire frame diagrams for development.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

2015 -2019	Bachelor	of	Information	Svstem	and	Networking	Engineering

St. Joseph University in Tanzania

2013-2015 Advanced Certificate of Secondary Education

Moshi Secondary School

2009-2012 Certificate of Secondary Education

Moshi Secondary School

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Sept 2022 to Present Ellipsis Digital Company

Tasks/Duties Performed

- Developing complex user interfaces UI.
- Utilize backend data services and contribute to increase existing data services API'S.
- Collaborating in writing and analyzing project requirements.
- Developed multiple bank reconciliation systems to help reconcile various Digital channels. i.e., MNO, Selcom, Cellulant, Bank GL
- Adapting Interface for modern internet applications using the latest technologies.
- Lead in various Projects and collaborate with team mates to deliver to customer solutions to help them solve their challenges.

Tasks/Duties Performed

- Develop, design and maintain cutting edge web-based Laravel and PHP school management system.
- Utilize backend data services and contribute to increase existing data services
 API'S
- Capturing of user requirements and translating them into database design.
- Refactor, optimize and improve the existing codebase for maintenance and scale.
- Write reusable, testable and efficient code.
- Frontend lead, Graphics design and UI/UX design.
- Create wireframes, storyboards, user flows, process flows and site maps to effectively communicate interaction and design idea.

Network Engineer

Nov 2019 to Jan 2020 Habari Node PLC

Tasks/Duties Performed

- Installation of Local Area Network, cabling.
- Fiber network installation.
- Network configuration and Monitoring.
- Server configuration.
- Maintenance and troubleshooting of network devices
- Installation and configuration of wireless devices such as mikrotik radios, routers, access point.

TRAINING & CERTIFICATION

- The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing by Google Digital Garage
- Angular Basic by Hacker Rank
- Android App Development by Google African Developers

KEY SKILLS.

Programming Skills

Proficient: MVC frameworks Laravel, PHP and

NodeJS.

REST APIs, SMS Communications and systems

integrations

Frontend: HTML5 & CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery,

Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap etc.

Frameworks: Angular, Vue JS and React.

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite and

Microsoft SQL.

REFEREES:

1. Mr. Albogast Kiyogoma

Software Engineer, INETS Company Limited, PO. BOX 33287 Dar-Es-Salaam

Mobile: +255 744 158 016 Email: albogast@shulesoft.com

2. Mr. Baraka Marango

Network Engineer, Liquid Telecom, P. O. Box 4204 Zanzibar Mobile: +255655100226

Email: baraka.marango@liquidtelecom.co.tz

3. Mrs. Naomi Newton Massamu

Monitoring and Evaluation Manager Pathfinder Organization

Mobile: +255759058269